Sai Surya Kalagani

Web developer

Passionate web developer with over 4 years of experience in developing websites and web applications using JavaScript frameworks such as React, is and Node, is. Proficient in working with MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, is, React, Node, is) and experienced in agile work environments.

ksaisurya304@gmail.com

1 416-829 6734



Brantford, ON, Canada



in https://www.linkedin.com/in/surya304

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer

VideoForm . MAY 2021 - DEC 2022

Node.js, Express.js, React.js, MONGODB, JavaScript based web-app

- Utilized Node.js, Express.js, React.js, and MongoDB to develop JavaScript-based web applications.
- Increased customer acquisition by 50% through the implementation of user-friendly features using Tailwind CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Express is, Node is, and MongoDB.
- Reduced internal server errors by 40% through the addition of various validations, enhancing user interaction and improving code structure.
- Solely responsible for project maintenance until deployment.
- Designed and developed an Analytics Panel that facilitated client onboarding.
- Integrated the extension with over 100+ CRM platforms, significantly reducing integration process time.
- Created a JavaScript Chat Bot widget, embeddable in any website, enabling clients to receive personalized video feedback.

Front-End Web Developer

GreyMetrics JAN 2019 - DEC 2020,

Node.js, Express.js, Angular.js, MONGODB, JavaScript based web-app

- Developed 25+ integrations for data retrieval and automated reporting in a JavaScript-based web application using Node.js, Express.js, Angular.js, and MongoDB.
- Collaborated with the Marketing and Development teams to define product requirements and roadmap.
- Designed the complete web app architecture and created 40+ reusable components.
- Built the user-facing web application using Angular 4 for the front-end and Node is for the backend.
- Configured application releases into test and production environments.

Front-End Web Developer

Aquo Digital AUG 2018 - DEC 2020,

HTM,CSS,JavaScript,JQUERY, MONGODB, DATATABLES, NODEJS,MVC,EJS

- Played a major role in developing, testing, and deploying a dynamic ecommerce website (https://www.vijayadiagnostic.com/) with an intuitive admin panel for content management.
- Collaborated closely with clients to understand their vision and incorporated their feedback into the development process.
- Worked with a team to create a 50-page static website (https://www.dubaidrivingcenter.net/).

EDUCATION

Post Graduate Diploma – Web Development

Conestoga College (Brantford, ON) 04/2023 - 08/2024,

Bachelor's in computer science

B V Raju institute of Technology in Hyderabad (INDIA) | 08/2014 - 05/2018,

SKILLS

- MERN (MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js)
- HTML5, CSS, Tailwind CSS, EJS
- JavaScript, ¡Query, Vue.js
- MongoDB, AWS S3, CloudFront
- REST API, AJAX
- Webflow
- Payment Gateway Integration (Stripe, Charge Bee)

PROJECTS

- https://www.videoform.com/
- https://greymetrics.com/
- https://www.sites60.com/
- https://www.vijayadiagnostic.com/
- https://www.dubaidrivingcenter.net/